Tauseef Ibne Mamun

tmamun@mtu.edu +1 (857)-574-9931 https://tmamun.netlify.app

407 Shelden Avenue, Apt 9, Houghton, Michigan, 49931

SUMMARY

Ph.D. student with specialized training in both human-computer interaction and behavioral psychology. Have a strong programming background. Experience in human factors analysis (qualitative and quantitative) and executing usability studies mainly in software and rail warning systems.

Research Tools/Methods

- Usability Evaluation (in-vehicular warning system, explainable AI system).
- In-field semi-structured user/driver interview. Design recommendation for chatbots in healthcare.
- Autonomous driving behavior analysis in the driving simulator.
- Data interpretation using advanced statistical modeling.

EDUCATION

Michigan Technological University | Houghton, MI Ph.D. Applied Cognitive Science and Human Factors

Expected 2023

Michigan Technological University | Houghton, MI

Artificial Intelligence in Healthcare Certificate

2021

Michigan Technological University | Houghton, MI

MS Applied Cognitive Science and Human Factors

2019 - 2021

Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology | Dhaka, Bangladesh

BS Computer Science & Engineering

2011 - 2015

EXPERIENCES

Michigan Technological University, Cognitive and Learning Sciences | Houghton, MI

Research Assistant

2019 - Present

2015 - 2018

Tasks:

- User behavior analysis in autonomous driving for user-centric explanations.
- Designing novel explanation methods for the human-Al teaming.
- Developing computational models for naturalistic decision-making scenarios.
- Behavioral analysis of drivers in rail crossings through mixed-method approach.
- Assessment of the usability of new in-vehicle systems in rail crossings.
 - ❖ Working/Worked with Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency and Federal Railroad **Administration** on different research projects.

Mighty Egg Technologies | Canada/Bangladesh

Programmer Analyst

Tasks:

Web and Mobile App Development.

Database Design & API development.

Software deployment in Amazon Web Service, Digital Ocean, Heroku.

Programming Expertise

R, Python, C, C++, Java, PHP, Ruby, PEBL

Git: GitHub (https://github.com/tm012)

FEATURED LEADERSHIP ROLES

- Vice President at Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology's Computer Science & Engineering Society 2014 - 2015
- Vice President at Bangladeshi Student Association at Michigan Technological University 2020 - 2021

INTERESTS

Photography | App Development | Video and Photo Editing